gatwickairport.com 2017-06-26

# Privacy & cookie policy | Gatwick Airport

**Please read carefully**

### 1\. Introduction

Gatwick Airport Limited (GAL) takes its obligations with regard to your personal information seriously. This privacy & cookie policy sets out the ways GAL handles your personal information collected via our websites (our “Websites") and through your participation and contribution in GAL related activities. GAL is registered as a data controller under the Data Protection Act. Any personal information collected by GAL is handled in accordance with applicable data protection legislation.

### 2\. The information we collect about you and the way we use it

You may be asked to give us personal details when purchasing, registering or subscribing to a Gatwick Airport service or product, taking part in customer research and surveys, service or product trials, entering competitions or providing feedback on various issues relating to GAL. If you give us your personal details we will inform you of the uses we make of that information at the time we collect it from you.

If you are giving us your personal details in the course of purchasing, registering or subscribing for a service, then we will of course use it in order to provide you with that service. We will use your information to communicate with you and to personalise our service. We may contact you by post, email, or telephone (including mobile SMS).

We may use your information to send you offers and news about our airport services or products or those of other carefully selected companies which we think may be of interest to you. Your confirmation emails (which may include details of bookings, airport services, product registration or subscription made through our Websites) may also include marketing material which we think may be of interest to you. We do our best to tailor this information so that it will be useful to you, but if at any time you no longer wish to receive it, you can opt out by following the instructions that we will give you with each communication.

Your data may be used for the following purposes: accounting, billing and audit, credit or other payment card verification and screening, immigration and customs control, safety and security, administrative and legal purposes, statistical and marketing analysis with a view to improving our products and services, the Websites and the user experience, systems testing, maintenance  and development, customer research and surveys,  customer relations and to help us in future dealings with you. If we use your information for the purposes of statistical or marketing analysis, your information will be made anonymous so you cannot be personally identified from it.

We may disclose your personal information to others where we are required or permitted to do so by law, or if you send us any material that is unlawful, offensive, abusive, threatening, defamatory, obscene, discriminatory or infringes the rights of anyone else, in order to prevent you from continuing to do so. If you are under 16 you must obtain consent from a parent or guardian before providing us with any personal information.

All personal information is held in a secure environment. All personal data that GAL collects is used in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998.

GAL may use third party processors to handle personal data collected, these processors may be located in the UK or abroad. When using processors, we ensure that appropriate contractual safeguards, as dictated by the Data Protection Act 1998, are put in place.

### 3\. Cookies

Gatwick Airport Limited collects information about your use of the Websites from cookies.

When you enter the Websites your computer will automatically be issued with a cookie. A cookie is a small text file that identifies your computer to our server. Cookies in themselves do not identify the individual user, just the computer used. If you do not know what cookies are or how to control them, we recommend you visit [http://www.aboutcookies.org](http://aboutcookies.org/) for detailed guidance. 

GAL cookies record those areas of the Websites that have been visited by your computer, for how long and what activity was undertaken on the Website. We do this so as to understand which are the most popular parts of the Websites, and also to improve your experience. For example, cookies that we use ensure that some promotional items, such as pop-ups and overlays, do not appear too many times on the same visit to the Website.

In addition, we would also like to make you aware that, although external to GAL, third party cookies are served on the Websites and can be used to track internet activity after a user has left the Website. Third party cookies usually have a long lifetime as they are ‘harvested’ and ‘refreshed’ whenever a user visits a page where the same or a similar cookie is being used.

You are not obliged to accept cookies. You have the opportunity to set your computer either to accept all cookies, to notify you when a cookie is issued, or not to receive cookies at any time. The last of these, of course, means that your experience of using the Websites may be impaired as we will be unable to personalise aspects of your use of the Websites.

**myGatwick:  **When the Remember Me box is ticked, a persistent cookie will enable us to recognise you when you re-visit the myGatwick website pages.

**Session Cookies**

We use a  **session cookie**  to remember your log-in for you and what you’ve put in the shopping basket. These we deem strictly necessary to the working of the website. If these are disabled then various functionalities on the site will be broken. More information on session cookies and what they are used for at <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/cookies/session-cookies-used-for.html>

**Persistent Cookies for Site Analytics and Performance**

**DoubleClick (Google)**  – this cookie is specific to the display advertising on Gatwick’s website. User data is anonymous. You can find out more generally about Google and its policies and principles as regards advertising at <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>

**Google Analytics**  – we use this to understand how the site is being used in order to improve the user experience. User data is all anonymous. You can find out more about Google’s position on privacy as regards its analytics service at <http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html>

**TagMan**  – this allows us to deploy different versions of our site to test (A/B Testing). User data is all anonymous. 

**Affiliate Window**  – Allows us to track affiliate advertisers and purchases. You can find out more about Affiliate Window on their site at [http://www.affiliatewindow.com](http://www.affiliatewindow.com/uk/)

**AddThis**  \- the service that runs some of our social sharing buttons. You can find out more about AddThis on their site at  [http://www.addthis.com](http://www.addthis.com/)  

**AppNexus** -the Platform uses cookies to associate non-PII with browsers and devices, so that clients can then use the information to select ads for delivery by the Platform. For a detailed privacy statement that applies to the Platform, see [http://appnexus.com](http://appnexus.com/)

**Google Adwords** – This cookie can save people's settings on certain websites and can sometimes be used to track how visitors get to and interact with websites. This can be used for remarketing purposes or to track progress to completion of a booking. You can view Google’s privacy statement at <http://www.google.com/intl/en_GB/policies/technologies/ads/>

**Qubit opentag –** this service allows us to enhance your online experience. For further detail please visit [http://www.qubitproducts.com/](http://www.qubitproducts.com/tag-management)

**Rocketfuel** – this turns online ads from an annoyance into a useful complement to your web-surfing experience. We want to deliver personalised, well-chosen ads to help you discover things that interest you—new websites, new products, new bargains. More information can be found at <http://rocketfuel.com/privacy-policy>

**VeInteractive** – this is used to improve user experience and collect information when you don’t complete your shopping cart. This allows us to ensure that you have all of the information that you need. For more details please visit [http://www.veinteractive.com](http://www.veinteractive.com/)

**Visual website optimiser** – this service uses cookies for testing purposes. The cookies are used to keep track of the Variation that a user has seen, the goals a user has completed and even the fact the user has become a part of the test or not. For more information please visit <http://visualwebsiteoptimizer.com/knowledge/what-are-the-various-cookies-used-by-visual-website-optimizer/>

**SessionCam** – this service is used to identify a unique user and a unique user session, allowing us to improve the experience that you have online. For more information please visit <http://www.sessioncam.com/privacy-policy-cookies/>

**Typekit by Adobe** -  to provide the Typekit service, Adobe may collect information about the fonts being served to you. The information is used to allow you to view the website as it should be seen. For more information visit <http://www.adobe.com/uk/privacy/typekit.html>

**Media6Degrees –** this is used to track behaviour of users on site, allowing us to serve you with relevant ads to your behaviour.

**MediaMath** – this allows us to provide you with relevant promotional material based on your activity on site. To find out more, please visit <http://www.mediamath.com/privacy/>

**Doubleclick Floodlight** – we use Floodlight to determine the effectiveness of our online campaigns in terms of both sales and user activity on our sites. For more information please see <https://support.google.com/dfa/partner/answer/186739?hl=en>

**Our own ad serving and management cookies**

We sell space on our website to advertisers. As part of this, we use several services to help us and advertisers understand what adverts you might be interested in. These cookies hold information about the computer - they don't hold personal information about you (i.e. it's not linked to you as an individual). But they might hold a record of what other websites you've looked at - so we could show you a car advert if you've previously visited a motoring website.

These are the services we use and how you can control those cookies. Please note that turning off advertising cookies won't mean that you are not served any advertising merely that it will not be tailored to your interests.

  * Doubleclick (advertising): Privacy policy at  <http://www.google.com/doubleclick/privacy/>and opt out via[ http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/)

  * Rubicon (ad partner): Privacy policy at <http://www.rubiconproject.com/privacy-policy/> and opt out at<http://www.rubiconproject.com/privacy/consumer-online-profile-and-opt-out>

**Other ad management cookies**

Advertisements on the Website are provided by other organisations. Our advertising partners will serve advertisements that they believe are most likely to be of interest to you, based on information about your visit to the Website and other websites. In order to do this, our advertising partner may need to place a cookie on your computer. These cookies hold information about the computer - they don't hold personal information about you (i.e. it's not linked to you as an individual).

For more information about this type of online behavioural advertising, about cookies, and about how to turn this feature off, please visit <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/>

Please note that turning off advertising cookies won't mean that you are not served any advertising merely that it will not be tailored to your interests. By entering our website and using it you are consenting to the use of cookies. However you are not obliged to accept cookies. If you do not however, this may mean that your experience of using the Websites may be impaired as we will be unable to personalise aspects of your use of the Websites.

### 4\. Your rights under the Data Protection Act

Under the Data Protection Act, you have the right to ask us what information we hold about you, the source of that information, and the uses to which it has been put. Such a request must be in writing and should be directed to the address below.

### 5\. Contact us

If you would like to update your information, modify your communication preferences, or if you do not want to receive marketing communications from GAL in the future, you can contact:

Data Protection Manager  
Gatwick Airport Limited  
5th Floor, Destinations Place  
Gatwick Airport  
West Sussex RH6 0NP

### 6\. Links to third party websites

This Privacy policy applies solely to the Websites and does not apply to any third party websites you may access from the Websites.

### 7\. Updates to the privacy & cookie policy

GAL may amend this privacy & cookie policy from time to time in order to meet change in the regulatory environment, business needs, or to satisfy the needs of our customers, properties, strategic marketing partners, and service providers. Updated versions will be posted to our Websites and date stamped so that you are aware of when the privacy & cookie policy was last updated.
